Best of enemies. Worst of friends.
Tom & Jerry is a comedy, family, animation film directed by Tim Story.
Tom the cat and Jerry the mouse get kicked out of their home and relocate to a fancy New York hotel, where a scrappy
employee named Kayla will lose her job if she can’t evict Jerry before a high-class wedding at the hotel.
Her solution?
Hiring Tom to get rid of the pesky mouse.
Kayla Forrester, played by Chloë Grace Moretz.
Terence Mendoza, played by Michael Peña.
Ben, played by Colin Jost.
Henry Dubros, played by Rob Delaney.
Chef Jackie, played by Ken Jeong.
Preeta, played by Pallavi Sharda.
Tom and Jerry (released as Tom & Jerry: The Movie in some territories) is a 2021 American live-action animated
comedy film based on the cartoon characters Tom and Jerry created by William Hanna and Joseph Barbera.
Produced by Warner Animation Group, it is the second theatrical film based on
the characters, following Tom and Jerry: The Movie (1992).
Directed by Tim Story and written by Kevin Costello, the film stars Chloë Grace
Moretz, Michael Peña, Colin Jost, Rob Delaney and Ken Jeong.
After years of languishing in development hell, including a live-action film in 2009 and an animated film in
2015, a live-action/animated hybrid film was announced in 2018 with Story attached as director.
Although it utilizes 3D computer animation, the production developed software and
used other techniques to mimic the look of traditional animation.
Filming took place at Warner Bros.
Studios, Leavesden from July to September 2019.
Tom and Jerry was theatrically released by Warner Bros.
Pictures in the United States on February 26, 2021,
alongside a one-month streaming release on HBO Max.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics and grossed $136
million worldwide on a $50‒79 million production budget.
The tone is lighthearted.